<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title></title><link href="http://daonb.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://daonb.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://daonb.github.io/</id><updated>2015-03-18T09:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Fear and Loathing in Israel</title><link href="http://daonb.github.io/fear-and-loathing-in-israel.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-18T09:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Benny Daon</name></author><id>tag:daonb.github.io,2015-03-18:fear-and-loathing-in-israel.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;By now, you’ve probably heard about the ugly elections we had in Israel. It's the third time in six years that I’ve been called to vote, and every time I’ve contributed long hours to develop open source tools helping voters make intelligent decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our site, Open Knesset, and it’s API got some extensive use this time around by many election games and application. These include our very own&lt;a href="http://bchirometer.oknesset.org/"&gt; Bchirometer&lt;/a&gt; app (Election Meter) which helps voters see which political parties voted according to the agendas they deem as important, and the&lt;a href="https://osubs.org/"&gt; Submarine,&lt;/a&gt; a game developed in cooperation with The Marker magazine, for choosing which politicians should head Knesset committees. Other apps based on our platforms include:&lt;a href="http://azlemi.org.il/"&gt; AzLemi&lt;/a&gt; ("So, who should I vote for?")&lt;a href="http://www.calcalist.co.il/local/articles/0,7340,L-3652901,00.html"&gt; Calcalist economic pre election tool&lt;/a&gt;, a&lt;a href="http://www.votemap.info/"&gt; visualization of Knesset voting patterns&lt;/a&gt;, and the fun&lt;a href="http://viz.calcalist.co.il/otr/web/"&gt; Bottom Line&lt;/a&gt; app."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve put a lot of effort into scraping the official site and, ordering and serving it’s data. For example, a bill has no ID in the official site and we need to collect information from the "Knesset Table", plenum votes and committee meetings and try and match their names to make it possible to track bills as the go through the legislation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last Knesset there were just  55 days when proposals were received at the Knesset Table. These days are spread between 3/13/2013 and 7/30/2014 and in them we scraped no less than 2794 private MKs bills for an average of  more than 50 proposals a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of this rain of proposals, only 58 got approved.  145 bills just managed to pass a pre-approval and 89 failed. Only 10 passed the first vote and just 6 are waiting for committee’s last corrections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this was all in vein. The elections were decided by emotions rather than logic with the leading parties using negative campaigns, spreading fear and loathing. It cost us quite a bit - around a quarter of a billion shekels was the bill last time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a special report by the State Comptroller, the 2013 elections, costed the Israeli public ₪241,801,302 ($60MM) out of which ₪195,079,702 came from taxpayers money and the rest from donations.  But this was not enough. Most of the parties ended the election with a debt bringing the total parties debt to ₪62,863,928. Halikud is the leader with a debt of ₪21,147,961 and then Sash with ₪12,271,028 and The Movement with the silver at ₪7,034,727.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sad thing is that with all this money, we got a society more fragmented and divided than ever before.  The arab citizens are feeling their basic rights have been challenged and prominent speaker of the left have been attacked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yehonatan Gefen, a popular author, poet, songwriter, journalist, and playwright was attacked at his home a couple of days after the election . Achinoam Nini, a singer &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/9hyU5qXNIs8?t=1m20s"&gt;that sang in the Vatican&lt;/a&gt; was attacked at the airport just a couple of days ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, these are clear signs, that our political system is broken and that instead of using open data to measure it we should start fresh. It’s time to restart the Knesset.  Instead of tracking the votes of the MKs, and other data from the Knesset we should develop a new system that makes it easy for activists to bring their issues to the public attention and for representative to join public initiatives and bring them to the Knesset and lead public discourse.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>There are only two hard things</title><link href="http://daonb.github.io/there-are-only-two-hard-things.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-26T09:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Benny Daon</name></author><id>tag:daonb.github.io,2014-06-26:there-are-only-two-hard-things.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are only two hard things in Computer Science: cache invalidation and naming things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phil Karlton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard this statement for the first time about five years ago and
I believe that not only it is true, but it has a grain of an even a bigger truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naming things is hard but hardly new. Confucius followers are working on “Alignment of Names” to align the names they use with things’ proper meanings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cache Invalidation is a bit more technical: To speed server response time, websites use cache.
The cache is a small, fast memory that temporarily stores results of complex, timely processes.
The hard part with cache is that you have to invalidate it when new data changes the processes result. If you fail, the data loses touch with reality and you’re serving stale data. To stay sharp, the server needs to detect stale data and invalidate it and it’s not easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mind uses a cache and it’s very hard to invalidate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I meet a friend do I really see him? Will I notice he has changed? Will I notice a new blister? A new religion? probably not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all carry stale caches in our minds. The stale part of the cache is made of
miconceptions and cleaning it up is hard work.
The internet can't help fs the mobile fire-hose of information is quite a distraction and I need to turn it down so my mind will have the cycles to work on trashing misconceptions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Thank you to all Github founders and their families</title><link href="http://daonb.github.io/thank-you-to-all-github-founders-and-their-families.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-18T00:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Benny Daon</name></author><id>tag:daonb.github.io,2014-03-18:thank-you-to-all-github-founders-and-their-families.html</id><summary type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;I guess things aren&amp;rsquo;t that simple and easy at github at the moment.  I&amp;rsquo;m watching it all from over 7,000 miles away and I believe I can feel the founders&amp;rsquo; and their families pains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we all want rapid growth, we tend to forget that growing at a ridiculous speed is impossible to manage.  Some are lucky, and become the billion-users-behemoth while most have a tougher ride.  It is like riding a crazy five years roller coaster enabling you to develop property worth over $100MM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, it&amp;rsquo;s very stressful to be a founder at such an endeavor.   It changes your live.  It makes your family and friends look at you differently, re-labeling you and taking you out of context.  You find yourself in a new place and it&amp;rsquo;s very stressful. As Newman said: &amp;ldquo;the mail never stops coming&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;rsquo;s even more stressful for the spouses.  Being at the passenger seat of this wild ride they help with navigation.  Sponses role is never  formal gut it&amp;rsquo;s a good thing they are involved.  IMO, it&amp;rsquo;s a good thing for a founder to be able to talk to their spouses and listen to their advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sorry to read the latest posts coming from github and I want to thank all github founders and their families for a great service to me and to the open source community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Coding FTW!&lt;/p&gt;

</summary></entry><entry><title>gov.uk design principles</title><link href="http://daonb.github.io/govuk-design-principles.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-17T22:50:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Benny Daon</name></author><id>tag:daonb.github.io,2014-03-17:govuk-design-principles.html</id><summary type="html">
  &lt;img class="halo" src="http://41.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m2az3lByDl1qzbo9no1_400.png" alt="GDS page" /&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/designprinciples"&gt;GDS design principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/designprinciples"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gov.uk"&gt;www.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Start with needs*&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;*user needs not government needs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The design process must start with iden&amp;shy;ti&amp;shy;fy&amp;shy;ing and think&amp;shy;ing about real user needs. We should design around those &amp;mdash; not around the way the &amp;lsquo;offi&amp;shy;cial process&amp;rsquo; is at the moment. We must&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The british gov reminds us again why they ruled the biggest empire&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Planning Game on a Pool Table</title><link href="http://daonb.github.io/planning-game-on-a-pool-table.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-04-14T12:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Benny Daon</name></author><id>tag:daonb.github.io,2010-04-14:planning-game-on-a-pool-table.html</id><summary type="html">
&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm just back from a great Open Knesset meetup. There were seven of us, a pool table and lots of free goldstar beer (thanks to amir from goldstar) in the "Rosa Parks". It was great fun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_54nzRYlF1Ss/S8ZApNSQaII/AAAAAAAAAiA/U8SX0f1Vuv4/s1600/IMG_0412.JPG"&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 600px; height: 450px;" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_54nzRYlF1Ss/S8ZApNSQaII/AAAAAAAAAiA/U8SX0f1Vuv4/s400/IMG_0412.JPG" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5460122674918353026" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We came to play with planning. Our project, &lt;a href="http://www.oknesset.org/"&gt;Open-Knesset&lt;/a&gt;, needs focus and the game delivered. We started with the &lt;a href="http://www.c2.com/cgi/wiki?PlanningGame"&gt;wiki definition&lt;/a&gt;, the ideas of &lt;a href="http://agilezen.com/tour/visualize"&gt;AgileZen&lt;/a&gt; and a pool table.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_54nzRYlF1Ss/S8ZE5qVKTwI/AAAAAAAAAiI/izPPor-wj18/s1600/setup.png"&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 600px; height: 450px;" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_54nzRYlF1Ss/S8ZE5qVKTwI/AAAAAAAAAiI/izPPor-wj18/s400/setup.png" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5460127355639582466" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As the game progressed the table filled with cards. Well, the left side did, the right was left empty, opening room for &lt;a href="http://michaeltrier.com/"&gt;empty thoughts&lt;/a&gt;.We decided to split: keep what's critical above the stick and what's important below it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_54nzRYlF1Ss/S8ZH5QaFjmI/AAAAAAAAAiQ/OKLi_SCJVAw/s1600/first+split.png"&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 600px; height: 450px;" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_54nzRYlF1Ss/S8ZH5QaFjmI/AAAAAAAAAiQ/OKLi_SCJVAw/s400/first+split.png" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5460130647215804002" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We left the table when we had our prime objective: Make our user go wow! and how to do it - serving a page that renders a glance at a Knesset Member. We cleared the table and focused on the information displayed on the member's page.  At that time, someone wanted to play pool, so we moved to a side table, opened one laptop with balsamiq and wireframed the page.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I had no idea it would end there, a pleasant surprise.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks to:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_54nzRYlF1Ss/S8ZKkBwoQVI/AAAAAAAAAiY/aqwjquD3Qrs/s1600/IMG_0411.JPG"&gt;&lt;img style="float: right; margin: 0pt 0pt 10px 10px; cursor: pointer; width: 200px; height: 150px;" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_54nzRYlF1Ss/S8ZKkBwoQVI/AAAAAAAAAiY/aqwjquD3Qrs/s200/IMG_0411.JPG" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5460133581041451346" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the ppl of the "Rosa Parks" for the place the service and the food&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Amir from Goldstar for the free beer&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="http://babylon5.wikia.com/wiki/Great_Maker"&gt;Great Maker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>A piece of burnt charcoal and a cave's wall</title><link href="http://daonb.github.io/a-piece-of-burnt-charcoal-and-a-caves-wall.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-09-21T22:50:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Benny Daon</name></author><id>tag:daonb.github.io,2008-09-21:a-piece-of-burnt-charcoal-and-a-caves-wall.html</id><summary type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
I use a lot of Web 2.0 sites like flickr, youtube, twitter, friendfeed and linkedin on a daily basis and I think they are elegant. I think the term I use to group them is crap. &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Web 2.0&lt;/span&gt; tells me nothing about what they have in common and confuses me when it comes to their history as it suggests it's all about a sock dog 2.0.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://msnbcmedia3.msn.com/j/msnbc/Components/Photos/070904/pets.widec.jpg"&gt;&lt;img style="margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px;" src="http://msnbcmedia3.msn.com/j/msnbc/Components/Photos/070904/pets.widec.jpg" alt="" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One of the things all those sites have in common is user contributions. We all do it, but why do we spend countless hours twitting, uploading, writing and editing? What is the motivation and what is the role-model we chase? I discovered quite a few role-models - David Willis for blogers, Lonely Girl for video, Linus for kernel coders, Randall Munro for comics and Guido van Rossum for python programmer to name a few.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To me they are all artists, or at least gifted artisans whose art will be grokked by future generations. Arts origins date way back, long before the sock dog:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/0/03/Lascaux-aurochs.jpg"&gt;&lt;img style="margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 320px;" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/0/03/Lascaux-aurochs.jpg" alt="" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
  Cave Paintings are paintings on cave walls and ceilings, and the term is used especially for those dating to prehistoric times.
  The earliest known European cave paintings date to 32,000 years ago.
  The purpose of the cave paintings is not known. The evidence suggests that they were not merely decorations
  of living areas, since the caves in which they have been found do not have signs of ongoing habitation.
  Also, they are often in areas of caves that are not easily accessed. Some theories hold that they may
  have been a way of transmitting information, while other theories ascribe them a religious or ceremonial purpose.
  &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cave_paintings"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
I don't think the caveman purpose was other than:
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  ...connecting with peers, achieving a certain level of fame, notoriety, or prestige, and the desire to express oneself.
  &lt;br /&gt; (from &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_generated_content"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;'s User Generated Content)
&lt;/blockquote&gt; 
The piece of charcoal grew to be a twitt, a post, a bookmark, a photo, a video. The cave's wall matured into Web 2.0 sites or as I think we should call them WallX.
&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>